Finding Aid for Monroe County (Mich.) records, 1819-1943
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Monroe County (Mich.) records 1819-1943
Monroe County (Mich.).
4 oversize folders
5 oversize volumes
0.6 linear feet (in 2 boxes)
86377 Cb 2; Cb Out.; CB Out.
Miscellaneous county records.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The provenance of the record group is uncertain.
No further additions to the records are expected.
The record group is open to research.
Monroe is a county located in southeastern Michigan, south of Detroit and Wayne County and north of Toledo, Ohio.
The record group has been arranged into the following series: School records; Elections; Taxation, assessments, etc.; Census reports; and Miscellaneous. Items of interest include school reports, 1835-1883 and school census, 1914 and 1920; election registrations, poll lists and election returns, 1820-1888; highway assessment and tax records, 1819-1943; assessment roll of Milan township, Michigan, 1902, lists and abstracts of sales of state lands, 1860-1899; tavern permits, 1836-1838; abstracts of permits, occupations and new establishments, 1830-1840; bonds, 1822 and 1841-1892; drain survey, 1861; certificates of sales of swamp lands, 1867; census reports of Port Lawrence township (later part of Ohio), 1827, and Ida township, 1837; military lists,1869-1886; and contracts of Monroe County Detecting Society (vigilance committee) for 1848 and 1853.
Subjects:
African Americans--Michigan--Monroe County.; Education--Michigan--Monroe County.; Elections--Michigan--Monroe County.; Ida (Mich.: Township); Land use--Michigan--Monroe County.; Michigan. Constitution (1835); Milan (Mich.: Township); Monroe County Detecting Society (Mich.); Ohio.; Port Lawrence (Mich.: Township); School census--Michigan--Monroe County.; Taxation--Michigan--Monroe County.; Vigilance committees--Michigan--Monroe County.
Genre Terms:
Census records.
- School records
  - Annual Reports of the School Districts 1883 (Folder 1)
  - Annual Report of the Board of School Inspectors 1838-1873 (various dates) (Folder 1)
  - Statistical Report of the School District 1916 (Folder 1)
  - School Census 1920 (Folder 1)
- Elections
  - To Legislative Council 1829, 1831, 1833 (Box 1)
  - Congressional Delegate 1820-1835 (Box 1)
    - 1820 (Box 1)
    - 1826, 1827, 1831 (Box 1)
    - 1833 (Box 1)
    - 1835 (Box 1)
  - Local 1826-1896 (Box 1)
    - 1826, 1829, 1832 (Box 1)
    - 1836, 1837, 1838 (Box 1)
    - 1857 (Box 1)
    - 1858, 1860, 1869 (Box 1)
  - State 1835-1850 (Box 1)
    - 1835 (Box 1)
    - 1837 (Box 1)
    - 1843-1846 (Box 1)
    - 1847 (Box 1)
    - 1848 (Box 1)
    - 1849, 1850 (Box 1)
  - Vote on Michigan Constitution 1835 (Box 1)
  - Vote on "equal suffrage to colored persons," 1850 (Box 1)
  - Local election registration lists, tallies of votes, etc. (Folder 2)
- Taxation, assessments, etc.
  - Auditor's reports of taxes paid (Folder 3)
  - Abstract of Assessment rolls (Folder 3)
  - Abstract of non residents lands ... to sell for taxes Tax lists (name, description of land, to whom sold, etc.) (Folder 3)
  - Non-residents Lands (Folder 4)
  - Rough draft of assessment rolls 1833 (Folder 4)
- State Tax Land Records / Financial
  - List of State Tax Land Subject to Purchase Under Section 136 of Act 206 1893 (Folder 4)
  - Sale of State Bids 1893 (Folder 4)
  - Assessment Rolls 1833-1835, 1840 (Volume 1)
  - Financial ledger circa 1831-1840 (Volume 2)
  - Abstract of Sales of State Tax Land in County of Monroe 1860, 1862-1866, 1868 (Volume 3)
  - Abstract of Sales of State Tax Land in County of Monroe 1880, 1884-1888 (Volume 4)
  - Abstract of Sales of State Tax Land in County of Monroe 1890-1894 (Volume 5)
- Census reports
  - Census report, Ida Township 1837 (Folder 4)
  - Census report, Port Lawrence Township 1827 (Folder 4)
- Miscellaneous
  - Speech describing collection; and first inventory of the materials (Box 2)
  - County Bonds
    - 1878 (Box 2)
    - 1880 (Box 2)
    - 1892 (Box 2)
  - War Bounty Bond 1865 (Box 2)
  - Drain Survey of Frenchtown Township 1861 (Box 2)
  - Tax Lists for Highways and Streets 1832-1840 (Box 2)
  - Bankruptcy papers of Martin Brower 1838 (Box 2)
  - Cashbook 1835-1836 (Box 2)
  - Declarations by County Officials 1820-1882 (Box 2)
  - Surety Bonds 1822-1871 (Box 2)
  - Tax Roll
    - 1819 (Box 2)
    - 1820 (Box 2)
    - 1823 (Box 2)
  - Tax lists 1836-1839 (and miscellaneous) (Box 2)
  - Tavern Permits
    - 1836-1837 (Box 2)
    - 1837 (Box 2)
    - 1838 (Box 2)
    - 1840 (Box 2)
  - Abstracts of permits, new establishments, etc.
    - 1830, 1833, 1836 (Box 2)
    - 1837-1838 (Box 2)
  - Poll List for Dundee Township 1840 (Box 2)
  - Military Lists 1869, 1885, 1886 (Box 2)
  - Apportionment of Primary School Money 1859, 1860 (Box 2)
  - Wolf Bounty Bond 1841 (Box 2)
  - Certificates of Sale of Swamp Lands 1867 (Box 2)
  - Promissory Notes 1823-1837, 2 folders (Box 2)
  - Monroe County Detecting Society (Box 2)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 2)
  - Notebook containing inventory of Monroe County records; and calendar of Monroe County courts files 1818-1818 et seq. (Box 2)